Swapnil Rane

Product (UI/UX) Designer

Q Thane, India

@ swapnilmr@outlook.com

9594 09 3535

www swapnilmr.github.io

A dribbble.com/swapnilmr

in linkedin.com/in/swapnilmr

Product (UI/UX) and Visual Designer with roots in Graphic Design. I've been crafting digital experiences for brands and products along with other creatives for over 8 years. Specialised in User Interface, User Experience, Branding & Identity, Design Systems and Art Direction.

Experience

UI/UX Designer | Shipwaves Online Limited, Mumbai

Nov 2018 - Present

Leading the build-out of the new design system, as well as the new visual language for India's leading online freight forwarder

- At Shipwaves, I have worked on a variety of projects, which include creating multiple design systems, shaping different modules of an online freight forwarding platform, branding and marketing material.
- Currently, I am focused on establishing Shipwave's design system, using Figma to develop our UI kit, partnering with developers and introducing the design system to stakeholders.
- I developed design tokens for color, typography, and spacing, and redesigned our system components.
- I was responsible for the design of RFQ Module. I also worked on redesign of other module which includes Shipments, Enquiries, Schedules, Shipment Planner, Tracking & Analytics.
- · I designed social media creatives, presentations and other marketing material for the brand.

Web/Visual Designer | 26FIVE, Mumbai

May 2016 - Sep 2018

- Directed UI/UX for websites and microsites projects and managed a team of two designers to ensure timely and high-quality project delivery.
- · Worked on front-end development with external vendor as well.
- Designed emailers, print materials, social media creatives for multiple clients.

Visualizer | TING, Mumbai

Jun 2015 - Apr 2016

 Designed banners, handouts, newspaper adverts, presentations, social media creatives, website designs for multiple clients.

Education

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology (Hons.) | University of Mumbai

2023 (Appeared)

Monsoon Course on HCI | Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

June 2023

Skills

UX Research & Design User Flows Wireframing

UI Design Prototyping Usability Testing

Visual Design Design Systems Branding

Softwares











